Ladies and gentlemen, friends, good morning.
Fuzhou in midsummer is vibrant with light and lush with greenery,
and it's here in this beautiful open city with picturesque landscape
that we gather at this hopeful time.
We are here to start the first epic advanced training program
for leading professionals in clean energy sector.
On behalf of China Energy Investment Corporation, I would like to extend a warm welcome to all
the participants and guests from the economic community.
Thank you for traveling such a long way to join us.
This training program is co-hosted by China Energy Investment Corporation and North China
Electric Power Corporation.
We have received careful guidance and strong support from the APEC Secretariat, Ministry
of Foreign Affairs of China, and the National Energy Administration of China.
We also appreciate the full support and careful organization from the Fujian Provincial Energy
Administration and other relevant departments, Longyuan Power and the School of Continuing
Education of North China Electric Power University.
I would like to express my sincere gratitude and respect to all leaders and colleagues
who have helped organize and support this event.
The year 2026 is a milestone for Asia-Pacific cooperation.
It's also the third time that China serves as APEC chair.
This year's APEC thing is building an Asia-Pacific community to prosper together.
The energy theme is fort and innovative as a synergistic Asia-Pacific energy community for all.
These themes set a clear direction and build common understanding for energy transition, green cooperation and mutual benefit in the region.
China Energy Investment Corporation and North China Electric Power University are jointly working to establish the Asia-Pacific Clean Energy Training Institute.
The Institute aims to serve epic economies through talent development, policy exchange, technology sharing, and industry collaboration.
This training program is a practical step by China to advance Asia-Pacific energy cooperation
and deepen regional green development.
It has important demonstrative and pioneering value.
Here participate other friends.
The theme of this training program is innovative practices in clean energy development.
It draws on the industrial trends of China energy and the academic expertise of North
China Electric Power University.
The program focuses on new power systems, new energy technology updates, and green business
integration.
We have designed high-quality professional courses.
We have also included cultural experiences like Chinese Intangible Cultural Heritage and tea culture.
We hope that through mutual learning, you will improve professional skills and gain new ideas.
We also hope that through cultural exchanges, you will build friendships and find common ground.
We look forward to sharing practical experiences and governance wisdom on energy transition.
Together, we will inject new momentum into Asia-Pacific green and low-carbon cooperation.
Ladies and gentlemen, the successful opening of this training program is a key step in building the Asia-Pacific Clean Energy Training Institute.
We know that a cooperative outcome can only thrive with sustained cooperation, broad participation
and joint commitment.
I would like to make a sincere call to all of you.
I hope you will not just be participants in this program, but also promoters and advocates
for the Institute's future development.
Please take what you have learned and experienced back to your economies.
Let all of your colleagues know about this platform and join it.
Let us work together to turn the Asia Pacific Clean Energy Training Institute
from a Chinese-led initiative into a long-term cooperation mechanism
that all parties in the region nurture and benefit from.
Let us deliver lasting results that stand the test of time for epic energy cooperation.
Finally, I wish this epic advanced training program a great success.
I wish all participants a rewarding and enjoyable stay in Fujian.
May you learn well, gain insights, have a smooth journey, and enjoy good health.
Thank you all.